James Kernicky

Springfield, PA | 484.432.9712 | jimkernicky@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Web Portfolio

SUMMARY

Experienced professional with 15 years experience servicing over 200 clients in a pet services company, and 12 years as an inventory analyst. Dedicated to elevating team performance and ensuring a unified approach to success. Leveraging effective communication and problem-solving skills to deliver outstanding stakeholder management.

SKILLS

Client Management, Communication, Time Management, Critical Thinking, Training/Education, Remote
Collaboration, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Access), Data Analysis, Inventory Management, Software
Development, cPanel (Zone Editor, phpmyadmin, Redirects, File Manager, Softaculous), Slack, Google Drive.

EXPERIENCE

Fairmount Pet Service, Owner, Philadelphia, PA (2009-Present)

- Provided pet services for 200+ clients, hired 7 employees to assist with clients, communicated with both clients and employees in person, and via email, phone, and text.
- Built website with Dreamweaver in 2009, converted it to WordPress in 2018, and employed graphic design and copyrighting principles in writing weekly blog posts.
- Site uses Cloudflare for caching, and has 85 pages/posts with custom CSS, optimized images, and on-page SEO.
- Created a Yelp account, Google My Business listing, and Facebook Business page to promote business.
- Utilized MS Excel to calculate annual revenue by client to prioritize scheduling.
- Achieved higher website speed performance through monthly performance audits.

Volunteer Service (May 2021-Present)

- Completed a WordPress site for a local non-profit, trained site owner on how to use WordPress and Elementor.
- Wrote the 301 redirect code for .htaccess file, improved Lighthouse performance by 25 points for Gamer site.
- Built WordPress.com site, created navigation menu and custom HTML elements for a political website.
- Trained WordPress blogger on using the features in the admin area, and set global styles in the Customizer.
- Utilized Slack huddles to communicate with site owners and teach them basic WordPress and web principles.

Topic Creator, The Hoth, Remote. (March 2020 to August 2020)

- Researched unique keyword phrases for the client used by the Topic Writers.
- Wrote SEO titles and Descriptions and provided related keyword phases not used in previous client articles.
- Ensured SEO Title and SEO Description met the minimum and maximum character requirements.

EDUCATION & COURSES

- Web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy (2023).
- Git Developer Workflow, Udemy (2021).
- Responsive Web Design certifications, freeCodeCamp (2021).
- WordPress Theme Development, Udemy (2020).
- Bachelor of Science in Operations Management, 1992 Drexel University (1992).